最重要的东西。
in the entire world.
我们所有的文明都依存于语言之上。
All of our civilization rests upon it.
那些终生致力于研究语言的人——
And those who devote their lives to studying it --
语言是怎么出现的， 人类的语言为什么有差异，
both how language emerged, how human languages differ,
与动物的交流系统有什么不同——
how they differ from animal communication systems --
是语言学家。
are linguists.
正统的语言学，或多或少仍是 个比较新的领域。
Formal linguistics is a relatively young field, more or less.
并且它揭示了许多真正重要的信息。
And it's uncovered a lot of really important stuff.
例如，人类的交流系统
Like, for example, that human communication systems
与动物的交流系统有相当大的差异，
differ crucially from animal communication systems,
所有的语言都有相当的表现力，
that all languages are equally expressive,